Wrege, Charles D. Collection of Audio-Visual Materials 6012 AV
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Charles D. Wrege Collection of Audio-Visual Materials
1921-2007
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Wrege, Charles D.
6012 AV
1.56 cubic feet
1.6 linear ft.
Audiovisual material.
7955863
Biographical / Historical
Charles "Chuck" Wrege finished his undergraduate degree in Upsala College, obtained his Masters degree at the New School fo Social Research and another Masters of Business Administration and his Ph.D. at NYU. He taught industrial management at Rutgers University for 30 years. He became a renowned historian, researcher and writer. He is regarded as a "National Treasure" by many in his field because of his expertise and the seminal research he has done in the area of management history.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5167: Charles D. Wrege Hawthorne Studies Research Data 5618: Charles D. Wrege Research Papers Regarding History of Management 5618 P: Charles D. Wrege History of Management Collection of Midvale Steel Company Photographs 6012m: Charles D. Wrege "Facts and Fallacies of Hawthorne" Doctoral Dissertation. 1961 6012: Charles D. Wrege Papers 6013 P: Charles D. Wrege Collection of Midvale Steel Company Photographic Negatives 6014: Charles D. Wrege Collection of History of Management Documents 6014 P: Charles D. Wrege Collection of History of Management Photographs 6054: Charles D. Wrege Collection of Additional Taylor Charts 6118 AV: Kheel Center AV Collection 6271: Charles D. Wrege Collection of International Management Institute Correspondence 6304: Charles Wrege Collection of Midvale Steel Company Index Cards
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives 227 Ives Hall Tower Road Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheelref@cornell.edu https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, January 30, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 17, 2016
Employees -- Training of; Borhek, Henry; Hawthorne, Taylor; Murdoch, John; Stogdill, Ralph M. (Ralph Melvin), 1904-1978; Wrege, Charles D.; Academy of Management; Peter James Company; Western Electric Company
7955863
- Western Electric Management Training, 1 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  #3
- Interview with E. Stuart Davis - Dec. 7, 1966 - on printing telegraph - Morkrum-Kleinschmidt (later Teletype Corp.) reperforator used to record output at Hawthorne - and 'undulator' mechanism used to draw output charts at Hawthorne, 2 (Box 1)
  #2 -- E. Stuart Davis died 9/21/1996
- Search for Schmidt talk, 3 (Box 1)
  #7
- Talk on Taylor's life, 4 (Box 1)
  #6
- 1966 interview with Henry Borhek (90 years old) - who with Taylor at Bethlehem in 1899 includes Robert T. Brown, Historian for the City of Bethlehem, 5 (Box 1)
  #4
- Church Synectics problem - Summer 1969 - "Problem Solving", 6 (Box 1)
  #8
- Peter James Co. tape - 1965, 7 (Box 1)
  #14
- In-Plant printing Association - Synectics tape, 8 (Box 1)
  #15
- Interview with John Murdoch, June 8, 1965 on what really influenced output at Hawthorne - 1924-28, Murdoch was Assistant Foreman in Relay Assembly Dept., 9 (Box 1)
  #1
- How to do Historical Research CD Wrege, 10 (Box 1)
  #5
- Small business, 11 (Box 1)
  #10
- Synectics Program to come up with a name for a garden center, 12 (Box 1)
  #12
- Rutgers Problem solving course - "Synectics" method. 1990, 13 (Box 1)
  #13
- Ralph Stogdill on Leadership - 8/11/1975, 14 (Box 1)
- Synectics Plastic bottle problem, 15 (Box 1)
  #9
- Management (Worker) as a poor example of Management History - 1995, 16 (Box 1)
  #1 - Dupl.
- Management History Research / Chuck Wrege -- 1995, 17 (Box 1)
  #18
- Management (worker) - As a poor example of Mgt.. History - 1995, 18 (Box 1)
  #17
- Tape of Sept. 20, 1996 on boxes of documents for Cornell Univ., 19 (Box 1)
  #16
- Tape on Archival Material sent to R. Strassberg at Cornell - 9/16/1979, 20 (Box 1)
- Management History according to Charles Wrege (1 of 2) (Box 2)
- Management History according to Charles Wrege (2 of 2) (Box 3)
- Hawthorne Film (1921) (Box 4)
- The Boxly Tour -- Friday, August 3, 2007 (Box 5)
- Hawthorne Film, 1921 (Box 6)